Matt Browne

New York, NY | 719-651-8943 | mbrowne108@gmail.com LinkedIn URL | Github | Portfolio

FRONT-END/FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in JavaScript-based programming specializing in React, as well as both Java Spring Boot and Ruby on Rails for backend. Possess strong skills in collaboration and project organization. Also spent fifteen years earning a Doctorate in Music Composition, supplementing the above with unique creative thinking skills, soft skills, and proactivity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript, React, Java, Spring Boot, Ruby, Rails, Active Record, Active Storage, Postgres, MySQL, CSS, Bootstrap

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Atlas of Curiosities - Github I Demo

Collection of user-added local historical sites incorporating Google Maps API.

- Incorporated Google Maps API to map each location and give real-time distance information to the user.
- Utilized Active Storage to include photos from each user's visit which is stored online via Cloudinary.
- Incorporated the Google Maps Geocoding API to convert addresses into coordinates and vice versa.
- Converted global state variables into a Redux framework to streamline code where state is used..

Star Trek: The Game - Github | Play

Top-down action game developed entirely using vanilla JavaScript on the HTML Canvas, no external libraries or frameworks.

- Fully mobile solar system, each planet with their own orbit around the sun, some with their own moons orbiting them, each at different speeds, including hundreds of individually moving asteroids.
- Klingon enemies with attacking and retreating Al.
- Scanning and tracking for both enemy ships and planets around the solar system.
- 8-bit chiptune music for the main menu and each planet.

Recipe Roulette - Github

App to present user with a random recipe from an external API based on ingredients they have in their pantry

- Backend made using Java Spring Boot and MySQL to store ingredients and favorited recipes
- React frontend with vanilla CSS styling

Quotordle - Github | Demo

Wordle-like game where you are given a famous movie quote (+more hints) and must name the movie.

- Utilized a rails backend to store all movie information as well as user scores.
- Styled using Bootstrap to have a simple, Wordle-like appearance.
- Created a leaderboard showing all users to keep the game competitive.

EXPERIENCE

Dev 10 New York, NY 12/2022 - 07/2023 Associate

- Took part in a comprehensive Java training course
- Worked on various projects and skill-building endeavors while interviewing for positions

Maestoso Music New York, NY 09/2016 - Present

Freelance Composer and Arranger

Doctor of Musical Arts, Music Composition

- Compose classical music for various ensembles ranging from opera to full orchestra.
- Handle a self-managed schedule of ongoing commission deadlines and performance dates.
- Collaborate closely with musicians, conductors, music directors, orchestras, and donors.

EDUCATION

Dev₁₀ New York, NY Full Stack Web Development, Java Spring Boot and JavaScript program 01/2023 - 04/2023

Flatiron School New York, NY Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 07/2021 - 04/2022

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

Ann Arbor, MI 09/2011 - 05/2016